PROFILE

Seeking a challenging position in Big data technologies to utilize my skills and abilities while being resourceful, innovative and flexible.

Overall 10+ years of experience in IT, and 6+ years of experience in Big data Technologies. Experience working in Hadoop, Spark and AWS (cloud platform).

CONTACT

PHONE:

+27 67 218 6503

Linked-In Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/shashidataengineer-jnb

EMAIL:

Shashireddy40@gmail.com

PORTFOLIO

https://shashireddy40.github.io/mypage

CERTIFICATIONS

ISTQB-CTFL

Big Data Engineering with Hadoop and Spark from E&ICT, IIT Roorkee

PERSONAL PROFILE

Full Name: SHASHIDHAR REDDY

Date of Birth: 10th May 1990

Languages Known: English, Telugu and Hindi

ACHIEVEMENTS

Employee of the Quarter FY17

HOBBIES

Chess Cricket Traveling

SHASHIDHAR REDDY

Senior Data Engineer (Apache Airflow, NiFi, Spark, SQL and Python) South Africa | India | Remote

EDUCATION

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, Hyderabad, India Bachelor of Technology in Aeronautical Engineering.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUMO.WORLD

Senior Data Engineer | South Africa | Remote (OCT 2020 – Present)

Eblocks Software (Client OLDMUTUAL SA)

Data Engineer | Johannesburg (Oct 2019-May 2020)

Sonata Software, India.

Big Data Engineer | Hyderabad January 2015–January 2019

IrusInfotech Pvt Ltd, India

QA Analyst | Hyderabad June 2011–January 2015

SKILLS

Languages:

· Python, Scala

Operating Systems:

Linux, Windows

RDBMS:

• RedShift, MySQL, MS Server

Big data Technologies:

- Apache Spark,
- Hadoop, Hive
- Delta Lake
- Airflow, Nifi

Utilities/Tools:

Git. Docker

Cloud Platforms:

AWS Services

PROJECT #1:

Title: JUMO Financial Platform Data Engineering Services Clients: Telecom Networks and Banks in Africa Continent

Location: South Africa | Remote Duration: OCT 2019 to Present

Tools Used: AWS, EMR, Spark, Python, SQL, Airflow, Nifi

Team Size: 5-6

Role: Senior Data Engineer.

Description:

JUMO has banking as a service platform, enabling real-time access to funds at the lowest possible operating cost. Integrating into JUMO's platform enables our partners to offer loans, savings and a wide range of financial choices to customers and providing a full digital banking services

Responsibilities:

- Gathering Data From Different Client locations with SFTP and API Services
- Maintaining data in Different Data warehouse systems such as Redshift and S3
- Building complete infrastructure to ingest, transform & store data for further analysis & business requirement.
- ETL Process with Low Cost running technologies for huge data.
- Creating Daily and Monthly jobs with Apache Airflow to generate reports and ETL Transformations

PROJECT #2:

Title: CBR-R (CONDUCT OF BUSINESS RETURN REPORT)

Client: OLDMUTUAL SA.
Location: Sandton, Johannesburg.
Duration: OCT 2019 to Present

Tools Used: Hadoop, SQL, Hive, Apache Sqoop, Hortonworks

Team Size: 5

Role: Data Engineer.

Description:

The Conduct of Business Return must be submitted to the Financial Services Board which is the Regulatory Authority for the CBR. The CBR is applicable to all Insurers carrying on either a Long-Term Insurance Business, or a Short-Term Insurance Business, or both. It calls for metrics on a number of aspects, dealing with the conduct of the insurer as it relates to policyholders. Policy numbers, new business, cancellations, surrenders, lapses, benefits, claims, complaints and commissions are the main focus areas.

Responsibilities:

- Design, create, build & maintain data pipelines
- Handling, transforming & managing Data using Big Data Frameworks.
- Taking care of the complete ETL (Extract, Transform & Load) process. Like Data ingestion, Data Transformation Using Apache Sqoop, Spark and Hive.
- Generating Reports for FSB(Financial Board of South Africa) Using Hadoop ecosystems.

PROJECT #3:

Title : TUI Travel Group

Brands : Thomson Airways, Amadeus System, British Airways.

Client : TUI UK, British Airways.
Location : Hyderabad, India.
Duration : Jan 2015 to Jan 2019

Tools Used : Hadoop, Hive, Spark, Sqoop, Cloudera

Cloud Technologies : AWS Team Size : 10

Role : Big Data Engineer.

Description:

TUI Group is a multinational travel and tourism company. It is the largest leisure, travel and tourism company in the world, and owns travel agencies, hotels, airlines, cruise ships and retail stores. TUI Travel Group have several UK-based tour operators Thomson Holidays and First Choice, by using this brands Passengers able to Book Flight tickets, Hotels and Holiday Packages with Cheapest Prices to Major European Countries

Responsibilities:

- Designing and implementing semi-structured data analytic platform leveraging Hadoop.
- Extensively used Hive/HQL or Hive queries to query or search for a particular string in Hive tables in HDFS.
- Implemented Spark using Scala and Spark SQL for faster processing of data.
- Exported the analyzed data to the relational databases using Tableau for visualization and to generate reports for the BI team.
- Developed recommended system with using Machine learning techniques such as scikit-learn and python libraries.

PROJECT #4:

Title : Grocer-kart

Client : Idea Logistics, Hyderabad.

Location : Hyderabad, India

Duration : June 2011 to November 2014

Tools Used : Quality Center, QTEST, SQL Server 2008.

Team Size : 5

Role : Senior Test Analyst (QA)

Description:

Grocer kart is an online shopping portal they do save on the infrastructure costs that we would otherwise have to incur if we had a physical store. Since at Grocer kart, the customer always comes first, we have decided to pass on our savings to you in terms of discounts on products. Customer will realize that most products are priced lesser than the MRP.

Responsibilities:

- Have a good understanding of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), involved in various phases like Requirement gathering, Analysis/Design, Development and Testing.
- Responsible for test scripts generation, testing and validation.
- Analyzing Functional Requirements, Gathering and managing the Test Data
- Assist in the assessment and planning of test efforts required for new functions/features under development
- Defect tracking, analyzing and bug reporting using QC.